Guide to the Dorothy Norman Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Dorothy Norman papers
1903-1996
YCAL MSS 792
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
140.65
181 boxes
0.42
(182 boxes)
The papers contain correspondence, writings, literary manuscripts, notes, subject files, scrapbooks, and printed material documenting Dorothy Norman's activities, writings, and publications including the journal she founded and edited, Twice A Year: a Book of Literature, the Arts, and Civil Liberties. The papers also document Norman's relationships with the photographer Alfred Stieglitz and his circle of artists and writers, in particular her involvement with his gallery An American Place, with her husband Edward A. Norman and their families, and with prominent Indians including Ananda K. Coomaraswamy and Indira Gandhi.
Norman, Dorothy, 1905-1997
Norman, Edward A., 1900-
Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dorothy Norman, 1965-1992. Bequest of Dorothy Norman, 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
Group I, Correspondence with Alfred Stieglitz and Edward A. Norman (boxes 1-67), is restricted until January 2, 2020. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Box 166 (sound recording): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Material related to Dorothy Norman's research and writings on Jawaharlal Nehru is held in the Dorothy Norman Papers, Special Collections Research Center, Syracuse University Libraries.
Dorothy Norman (1905-1997)
The American editor, author, photographer, and social activist Dorothy Stecker Norman was born March 28, 1905, in Philadelphia, the daughter of Louis and Esther Stecker. She attended Smith College and the University of Pennsylvania, and took classes at the Barnes Foundation in Merion, Pennsylvania. In 1925 she married Edward Albert Norman (1900-1955), the son of Chicago philanthropist Aaron E. Norman, and settled with him in New York City. There she became involved with the American Civil Liberties Union and other progressive organizations; in later years Norman became a founding member of New York's Liberal Party, was a member of the Americans for Democratic Action, and served on the boards of the New York Urban League and the National Urban League. The Dorothy and Edward Norman were also arts patrons, and their town house at 124 East 70th Street was designed for them by the Swiss architect William Lascaze (1896-1969) in the early 1940s.
In 1927 Dorothy Norman met the American photographer Alfred Stieglitz (1864-1946) at his exhibition venue The Intimate Gallery, and for the next twenty years she was mentored by him, and he encouraged her interest in making photographs. In turn, she became his assistant, fundraiser, and financial manager of his final exhibition gallery, An American Place, which operated at 509 Madison Avenue from 1929 to 1950. Also interested in literature, Norman founded and edited a journal, Twice A Year: a Book of Literature, the Arts, and Civil Liberties, which she published from 1938 to 1946. In addition to her weekly column in the New York Post (1942-1949), she wrote, edited, published, or contributed to several publications on Stieglitz, the painter John Marin, and Indian statesmen she knew and admired, including Jawaharlal Nehru and Indira Gandhi. Her autobiography, Encounters: a Memoir, was published in 1987. Dorothy Norman died in East Hampton, New York, on April 12, 1997.
Scope and Contents
The papers contain correspondence, writings, literary manuscripts, notes, subject files, scrapbooks, and printed material documenting Dorothy Norman's activities, writings, and publications, including the journal she founded and edited, Twice A Year: a Book of Literature, the Arts, and Civil Liberties. The papers also document Norman's relationships with the photographer Alfred Stieglitz and his circle of artists and writers, with her husband Edward A. Norman and their families, and with prominent Indians including Ananda K. Coomaraswamy and Indira Gandhi.
The collection does not contain original photographs by Dorothy Norman or Alfred Stieglitz, or materials related to her writings on Jawaharlal Nehru.
Arrangement
Organized into four groupings: I. Correspondence with Alfred Stieglitz and Edward A. Norman, 1924-1981. II. Pre-1990 Acquisitions, 1908-1983. III. October 1991 Acquisition, 1903-1989. IV. April 1997 Acquisition, 1908-1996.
Twice a year; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Scrapbooks -- United States -- 20th Century; Tape recorders -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Editors -- United States -- 20th Century; Beecher, John, 1904-1980; Borgese, Giuseppe Antonio, 1882-1952; Brett, Dorothy, 1883-1977; Coomaraswamy, Ananda K. (Ananda Kentish), 1877-1947; Enters, Angna, 1897-1989; Gandhi, Indira, 1917-1984; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Graves, Morris, 1910-2001; Lescaze, Mary Hughes, 1901-1983; Lescaze, William, 1896-1969; Marin, John, 1870-1953; Meyer, Agnes E., 1887-1970; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990; Nin, Anaïs, 1903-1977; Norman, Dorothy, 1905-1997; Norman, Edward A., 1900-; Rosenfeld, Paul, 1890-1946; Ross, Cary; Steichen, Edward, 1879-1973; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946; Strand, Paul, 1890-1976; Sykes, Gerald, 1903-; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Varèse, Edgard, 1883-1965; Williams, William Carlos, 1883-1963; American Place (Gallery); Twice a Year Press
- Correspondence with Alfred Stieglitz and Edward A. Norman, 1924-1981; 1; 27.94; 67 boxes
  Arrangement
  Organized under three headings: Alfred Stieglitz, Edward A. Norman, and Other.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 2, 2020. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Alfred Stieglitz and Dorothy Norman Letters
    Arranged chronologically. Undated material is filed at the end of the list.
    - 1927 April 6 - 1929 July (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
    - 1929 July - 1930 April (Box 2, Folder 16-32)
    - 1930 May - July (Box 3, Folder 33-39)
    - 1930 July - October (Box 4, Folder 40-48)
    - 1930 November - 1931 July (Box 5, Folder 49-66)
    - 1931 July - September (Box 6, Folder 67-73)
    - 1931 September - 1932 June (Box 7, Folder 74-86)
    - 1932 June - July (Box 8, Folder 87-92)
    - 1932 July (Box 9, Folder 93-97)
    - 1932 July - August (Box 10, Folder 98-102)
    - 1932 August (Box 11, Folder 103-107)
    - 1932 August - September (Box 12, Folder 108-112)
    - 1932 September (Box 13, Folder 113-118)
    - 1932 September - November (Box 14, Folder 119-124)
    - 1932 October - 1933 January (Box 15, Folder 125-131)
    - 1933 February - April (Box 16, Folder 132-137)
    - 1933 May - July (Box 17, Folder 138-144)
    - 1933 July - August (Box 18, Folder 145-149)
    - 1933 August - September (Box 19, Folder 150-154)
    - 1933 September (Box 20, Folder 155-160)
    - 1933 September - December (Box 21, Folder 161-166)
    - 1933 December - 1934 March (Box 22, Folder 167-175)
    - 1934 April - July (Box 23, Folder 176-185)
    - 1934 July - August (Box 24, Folder 186-191)
    - 1934 August - September (Box 25, Folder 192-196)
    - 1934 September - 1935 March (Box 26, Folder 197-204)
    - 1935 March - April (Box 27, Folder 205-211)
    - 1935 May - June (Box 28, Folder 212-218)
    - 1935 June - August (Box 29, Folder 219-225)
    - 1935 September - 1936 February (Box 30, Folder 226-232)
    - 1936 February - May (Box 31, Folder 233-240)
    - 1936 May - September (Box 32, Folder 241-248)
    - 1936 October - 1937 February (Box 33, Folder 249-257)
    - 1937 March - June (Box 34, Folder 258-264)
    - 1937 June - July (Box 35, Folder 265-271)
    - 1937 July - August (Box 36, Folder 272-278)
    - 1937 September - December (Box 37, Folder 279-285)
    - 1937 December - 1938 February (Box 38, Folder 286-292)
    - 1938 March - May (Box 39, Folder 293-300)
    - 1938 June - July (Box 40, Folder 301-307)
    - 1938 July - August (Box 41, Folder 308-313)
    - 1938 August - September (Box 42, Folder 314-319)
    - 1938 October - 1939 May (Box 43, Folder 320-333)
    - 1939 June - July (Box 44, Folder 334-340)
    - 1939 August - September (Box 45, Folder 341-348)
    - 1939 October - 1940 April (Box 46, Folder 349-359)
    - 1940 April - July (Box 47, Folder 360-368)
    - 1940 July - August (Box 48, Folder 369-373)
    - 1940 September - December (Box 49, Folder 374-383)
    - 1941 January - May (Box 50, Folder 384-392)
    - 1941 May - July (Box 51, Folder 393-399)
    - 1941 July - August (Box 52, Folder 400-405)
    - 1941 September - November (Box 53, Folder 406-414)
    - 1941 December - 1942 May (Box 54, Folder 415-426)
    - 1942 May - July (Box 55, Folder 427-434)
    - 1942 July - August (Box 56, Folder 435-441)
    - 1942 August - 1943 January (Box 57, Folder 442-449)
    - 1943 January - June (Box 58, Folder 450-462)
    - 1943 July - 1944 June (Box 59, Folder 463-473)
    - 1944 July - August (Box 60, Folder 474-480)
    - 1944 September - 1945 June (Box 61, Folder 481-489)
    - 1945 July - August (Box 62, Folder 490-497)
    - 1945 September - 1946 April (Box 63, Folder 498-507)
    - 1946 May - July (Box 64, Folder 508-510)
    - Undated (Box 64, Folder 511-517)
  - Edward A. Norman and Dorothy Norman Letters
    - 1924 - 1933 March / April (Box 65, Folder 518-528)
    - 1933 March - 1943 (Box 66, Folder 529-544)
    - 1944 - 1955 (Box 67, Folder 545-560)
    - Undated (Box 67, Folder 561-564)
  - Other Letters
    - Two letters from Dorothy Norman to David Schoonover, Beinecke Library, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 565)
    - Letters from others to Alfred Stieglitz, 1954, undated (Box 67, Folder 566)
    - Correspondence to Dorothy & Edward A. Norman from others, 1925-1950 (Box 67, Folder 567-569)
    - Newspaper clippings and third-party correspondence, 1942-1956 (Box 67, Folder 570)
- Pre-1990 Acquisitions, 1908-1983; 2; 25.25; 28 boxes
  Organized under six headings: Dorothy Norman Correspondence, Alfred Stieglitz Correspondence, Literary Manuscripts, An American Place Administrative Files, America and Alfred Stieglitz Administrative Files, and Twice A Year Administrative Files.
  - Dorothy Norman Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Unsorted material is filed at the end of the list.
    - "A" General, 1937-1961; 2 (Box 68)
    - A. P. Watt & Son, 1939 (Box 68)
    - A. and S. Lyons, Inc., 1938-1939 (Box 68)
    - Abel, Lionel, 1937-1947, undated (Box 68)
    - Abrams, Ray H. (Ray Hamilton), 1938-1941 (Box 68)
    - Acosta, Mercedes de, 1952-1953, undated (Box 68)
    - Adams, Ansel, 1939-1951 (Box 68)
    - Adler, Miriam, 1945-1946 (Box 68)
    - Agha, M. F., undated (Box 68)
    - Albee, George, 1937-1940, undated (Box 68)
    - Albright Art Gallery (Buffalo, N.Y.), 1947-1951 (Box 68)
    - Alexander, Sidney, 1939-1940 (Box 68)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1940-1949, undated (Box 68)
    - Allinson, Brent D. (Brent Dow), 1938-1939 (Box 68)
    - Almasy, Otto, 1946 (Box 68)
    - Alsberg, Henry G. (Henry Garfield), 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Altripp, Alo, 1948, undated (Box 68)
    - Alvarez Bravo, Manuel, 1955, undated (Box 68)
    - Amann, Douglas M., 1947 April 3 (Box 68)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1938-1940 (Box 68)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1948 March 22 (Box 68)
    - American Library Association, 1938-1948 (Box 68)
    - The American Magazine of Art, 1934-1937 (Box 68)
    - The American Scholar, 1940-1942 (Box 68)
    - Ames, Elizabeth, 1942-1943 (Box 68)
    - Amram, Emilie, 1938-1947, undated (Box 68)
    - Anderson, Charles B., 1938 (Box 68)
    - Anderson, Edith, 1947-1948 (Box 68)
    - Anderson, Eleanor, 1942-1946 (Box 68)
    - Anderson, Forrest, 1939-1947 (Box 68)
    - Anderson, Saga, 1947 February 3 (Box 68)
    - Anderson, Sherwood, 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Andrews, Edward Deming, 1937 (Box 68)
    - Annan, David, 1953-1954 (Box 68)
    - Annixter, Jane, 1937-1939 (Box 68)
    - Anshen, Ruth Nanda, 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Antioch College, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Appel, Benjamin, 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1952 May 1 (Box 68)
    - Araujo, Alvaro A., 1942-1948, undated (Box 68)
    - Arden, Elizabeth, 1947, undated (Box 68)
    - Ardrey, Robert, 1937 (Box 68)
    - Arendt, Hannah, 1947-1952 (Box 68)
    - Arensberg, Walter, 1947, undated (Box 68)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Ascoli, Max, 1938-1946 (Box 68)
    - Associated Book Service, Inc., 1947-1950 (Box 68)
    - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1937-1946 (Box 68)
    - "B" General, 1939-1963; 2 (Box 68)
    - Bacon, Peggy, 1949 January 11 (Box 68)
    - Baldwin, Roger, 1937-1948 (Box 68)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1942 (Box 68)
    - Barker, Margaret T., 1938-1940 (Box 68)
    - Barnard, Mary, 1938-1940 (Box 68)
    - Barnes, Alfred, 1942-1957 (Box 68)
    - Barr, Alfred, 1946-1953 (Box 68)
    - Barr, Pelham, 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Bartlett, A. W., 1948 March 3 (Box 68)
    - Barton, Betsey, 1946-1959 (Box 68)
    - Batlivala, Bhicoo, 1940 (Box 68)
    - Bauer, Catherine K., 1937-1957 (Box 68)
    - Baur, John I. H. (John Ireland Howe), 1949 (Box 68)
    - Beam, Lura, 1938-1939 (Box 68)
    - Beamish, Rae, 1938-1940 (Box 68)
    - Beard, Mary, 1937-1941 (Box 68)
    - Beaudoin, Kenneth Lawrence, 1939 (Box 68)
    - Beauvoir, Simone de, 1937-1947 (Box 68)
    - Becker, Edwin J., 1945-1948 (Box 68)
    - Beckers, William, 1946 December 16 (Box 68)
    - Beecher, John, 1940-1957, undated; 2 (Box 68)
    - Béhaine, René, 1937-1938, undated (Box 68)
    - Berendt, Walter C., 1936-1938 (Box 68)
    - Behrens, Ellen, 1947, undated (Box 68)
    - Behmens, Alan, 1947 August 4 (Box 68)
    - Belitt, Ben, 1938-1941 (Box 68)
    - Benardete, M. J. (Maír José), 1938-1939 (Box 68)
    - Bende, Julien, 1938 (Box 68)
    - Benedict, Ruth, 1941 (Box 68)
    - Benson, Emanuel M., 1937-1946 (Box 68)
    - Bentley, Eric, 1946, undated (Box 68)
    - Benton, Walter, 1937-1943 (Box 68)
    - Berg, A. A., 1947 February 14 (Box 68)
    - Bergamín, José, 1939 (Box 68)
    - Berlack, Harris, 1939 (Box 68)
    - Berlin Museum of Fine Arts, 1951-1952 (Box 68)
    - Berman, Harold, 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Bernard Grasset (Firm), 1937-1939 (Box 68)
    - Bernstein, Aline, 1937-1938, undated (Box 68)
    - Bernstein, Henri, 1946-1948, undated (Box 68)
    - Bernstein, Philip, 1938, undated (Box 68)
    - Best, Marshall A., 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Bethurum, Dorothy, 1937 (Box 68)
    - Briddle, George, undated (Box 68)
    - Bier, Elmira, 1946-1952 (Box 68)
    - Billikopf, Jacob, 1946 December 5 (Box 68)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1937-1938 (Box 68)
    - Blackmur, R. P. (Richard P.), 1937 (Box 69)
    - Blenheim Club, 1949 March 9 (Box 69)
    - Blitzstein, Marc, 1937-1939 (Box 69)
    - Bloch, Ernst, 1937-1946 (Box 69)
    - Bloch, Suzanne, 1937-1941 (Box 69)
    - Blum, Frances, 1939-1942 (Box 69)
    - Blumenthal, Joseph, 1938 (Box 69)
    - Book Find Club, 1946-1948 (Box 69)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1938-1940 (Box 69)
    - Books Abroad, 1938-1939 (Box 69)
    - Borden, Fanny, 1939 (Box 69)
    - Borg, Frances, 1947-1948, undated (Box 69)
    - Borg, John, 1946, undated (Box 69)
    - Borgese, Giuseppe Antonio, 1938-1952, undated; 2 (Box 69)
    - Boulanger, Nadia, 1940-1941, undated (Box 69)
    - Bourgeois, Maria Theresa, 1954, undated (Box 69)
    - Boursault, Marie K., 1948-1954 (Box 69)
    - Bovey, John, 1939-1947, undated (Box 69)
    - Bowles, Paul, 1935-1938, undated (Box 69)
    - Boyd, James, 1941 (Box 69)
    - Bradfield, Margaret, 1947 February 25 (Box 69)
    - Bradley, Jennie, 1954-1958 (Box 69)
    - Bragdon, Claude, 1938-1939 (Box 69)
    - Braisted, Paul J., 1958-1960 (Box 69)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1937-1942 (Box 69)
    - Brant, Irving, 1937-1939 (Box 69)
    - Brecht, Bertolt, 1946-1947 (Box 69)
    - Breit, Harvey, 1938-1958, undated (Box 69)
    - Breton, André, 1941 (Box 69)
    - Brett, Dorothy, 1934-1960, undated; 4 (Box 69)
    - Breuer, Bessie, 1949, undated (Box 69)
    - Brewer, Joseph, 1947 February 19 (Box 69)
    - Brinnin, John, 1952 (Box 69)
    - Brinton, Christian, undated (Box 69)
    - Britchie, Jerome, 1940-1941 (Box 69)
    - Brixey, B., 1947 February 4 (Box 69)
    - Broad, D. D., 1937 (Box 69)
    - Broch, Hermann, 1941 (Box 69)
    - Brockway, George P., 1946 (Box 69)
    - Brod, Max, 1937-1941 (Box 69)
    - Bronstein, Sidney, 1947 February 18 (Box 69)
    - Brooklyn Museum, 1954 April 13 (Box 69)
    - Brooks, Charles Van Wyck, 1939-1947 (Box 69)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1937-1947 (Box 69)
    - Broomell, Sally, 1946 (Box 69)
    - Brown, F. A., 1947 February 18 (Box 69)
    - Brown, John L., 1946-1959 (Box 69)
    - Brown, Eleanor, 1947 (Box 69)
    - Bryan, John Stewart, 1948-1949 (Box 69)
    - Bryan, Mackenty, 1953 (Box 69)
    - Bryan, William, 1947, undated (Box 69)
    - Bryan, W. B. (Wilhelmus Bogart), 1937-1940 (Box 69)
    - Bryher, 1937-1939 (Box 69)
    - Bryner, Edna, 1946-1949 (Box 69)
    - Buber, Martin, 1950-1952 (Box 69)
    - Buchwalter, Theodore, 1949 (Box 69)
    - Buffet, Gabrielle, 1954 March 23 (Box 69)
    - Buhlig, Richard, 1947 (Box 69)
    - Bull, Nina, 1949 February 10 (Box 69)
    - Burgum, Edwin Berry, 1937-1941 (Box 69)
    - Burke, Kenneth, 1937-1940 (Box 69)
    - Buttrick, William, 1939 (Box 69)
    - "C" General, 1937-1962, undated; 2 (Box 69)
    - Caetani, Marguerite, 1953-1955 (Box 69)
    - Cahill, Holger, 1944 August 29 (Box 69)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes letter to Alfred Stieglitz.
    - Calas, Nicolas, 1941-1948, undated (Box 69)
    - Callahan, Harry, 1942-1943 (Box 69)
    - Calder, Alexander, 1955-1956 (Box 69)
    - Calmon, Claude-Odette, 1938, undated (Box 69)
    - Camus, Albert, 1946-1957, undated (Box 69)
    - Cane, Melville, 1947 March 12 (Box 69)
    - Cantwell, Robert, 1937-1939 (Box 69)
    - Capalbo, Carmen, 1953-1958 (Box 69)
    - Cardoza, Benjamin N. & Justice, 1937 (Box 69)
    - Carey, Graham, 1937-1938 (Box 69)
    - Carey Press Corporation, 1939-1940 (Box 69)
    - Carles, Mercedes, 1949 (Box 69)
    - Carlson, W. K., 1947 March 20 (Box 69)
    - Carlton, Margaret, undated (Box 69)
    - Carnegie Museum, 1949 January 17 (Box 69)
    - Carter, Sidney, 1947 March 20 (Box 69)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henri, 1946-1948, undated (Box 69)
    - Cayton, Horace R. (Horace Roscoe), 1945-1947 (Box 69)
    - Cerf, Bennett, 1938-1945 (Box 69)
    - Chabot, Maria, 1947 March 25 (Box 69)
    - Chambrun, Jacques, 1938-1939 (Box 69)
    - Champlin's Encyclopedia for Young People, 1946 (Box 69)
    - Chaffee, G., 1937-1938 (Box 69)
    - Chagall, Ida, 1948-1955 (Box 69)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1938 (Box 69)
    - Cheek, Leslie, Jr., 1948-1949 (Box 69)
    - Cheney, Sheldon, 1946 (Box 69)
    - Chester County Historical Society (West Chester, Pa.), 1954 (Box 69)
    - Chevalier, Haakon, 1941-1942 (Box 69)
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola, 1939-1941, undated (Box 69)
    - Child Bayley, R. (Roger), 1946-1948 (Box 69)
    - Childs, Harwood L. (Harwood Lawrence), 1937-1939 (Box 69)
    - Chisholm, Hugh, 1951 November 20 (Box 69)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1949 (Box 69)
    - Church, Henry, 1939 (Box 69)
    - Church, Ralph, 1937 (Box 69)
    - Cincinnati Modern Art Society, 1947-1949 (Box 70)
    - City Art Museum of St. Louis, 1947-1952 (Box 70)
    - City Library Association (Springfield, Mass.), 1951 August 6 (Box 70)
    - Clairouin, Denyse, 1937-1938 (Box 70)
    - Clark, Grenville, 1938-1940 (Box 70)
    - Clark, Kenneth, 1939-1944, undated (Box 70)
    - Clurman, Harold, 1937-1948 (Box 70)
    - Coakley, Elizabeth, 1941 (Box 70)
    - Cobham, G. H., undated (Box 70)
    - Codman, Florence, 1937-1942 (Box 70)
    - Cohen, Eli E., 1941, undated (Box 70)
    - Cohen, Morris Raphael, 1937-1938 (Box 70)
    - Cohn, Erich, 1947 May 12 (Box 70)
    - College of the City of New York, 1949 January 13 (Box 70)
    - Colton, Samuel, 1951 (Box 70)
    - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1949 January 17 (Box 70)
    - Colwell, Virginia M., 1947 March 4 (Box 70)
    - Commager, Henry Steele, 1941 (Box 70)
    - Commissioner of Internal Revenue, 1938-1951 (Box 70)
    - Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America, 1943-1945 (Box 70)
    - The Commonweal, 1946 (Box 70)
    - Constable, W. G. (William George), 1947 February 28 (Box 70)
    - Cook, Ruth D., undated (Box 70)
    - Coomaraswamy, Ananda K. (Ananda Kentish), 1936-1959 (Box 70)
    - Coomaraswamy, Dona Luisa, 1931-1960 (Box 70)
    - Cooney, James P., 1938-1953 (Box 70)
    - Copland, Aaron, 1937-1953 (Box 70)
    - Corey, Paul, 1938 (Box 70)
    - Cornish, Anne, 1938-1943 (Box 70)
    - Corpron, Carlotta M., 1947 (Box 70)
    - Coryell, Abby Hedge, 1947 February 14 (Box 70)
    - Cosgrave, John O'Hara, 1946-1949 (Box 70)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1937-1946 (Box 70)
    - Cox, Sidney, 1939-1941 (Box 70)
    - Crane, Milton, 1937-1946 (Box 70)
    - Craven, Thomas, 1947 (Box 70)
    - Creekmore, Hubert, 1940, undated (Box 70)
    - Crego, Martha, 1943-1945, undated (Box 70)
    - Crews, Judson, 1945-1947 (Box 70)
    - Crippen, Harlan R. (Harlan Robert), 1940-1946 (Box 70)
    - Crosby, Caresse, 1952-1955, undated (Box 70)
    - Crowell, Priscilla, 1937, undated (Box 70)
    - Crowley, Joseph, 1941-1943 (Box 70)
    - Crowninshield, Frank, 1938-1946 (Box 70)
    - Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1937-1949 (Box 70)
    - Cunningham, Imogen, 1947 (Box 70)
    - Curie, Eve, 1943 (Box 70)
    - Curry, W., 1937-1938 (Box 70)
    - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1937-1949 (Box 70)
    - Curtis, Thomas Quinn, 1939 (Box 70)
    - Curtiss, Mina, 1953-1955, undated (Box 70)
    - Cushman, Robert E., 1941 (Box 70)
    - "D" General, 1928-1959; 2 (Box 70)
    - Dahlberg, Edward, 1937-1941 (Box 70)
    - The Dalton Schools, 1941 (Box 70)
    - Daniel and Florence Guggenheim Foundation, 1937-1942 (Box 70)
    - Dartmouth College. Library, 1954 (Box 70)
    - The Darvin Press, 1939 (Box 70)
    - Dasberg, Andrew, 1949, undated (Box 70)
    - Davidson, Elizabeth, 1931-1954 (Box 70)
    - Davidson, Gustav, 1939-1941, undated (Box 70)
    - Davidson, Marshall, undated (Box 70)
    - Davidson, Sylvia B., 1948 (Box 70)
    - Davis, James E., 1949 (Box 70)
    - Davis, Renée, 1937, undated (Box 70)
    - Davisson, Elizabeth Derr, undated (Box 70)
    - De Casseres, Bio, 1947 (Box 70)
    - De Jong, David Cornel, 1937-1940 (Box 70)
    - Delaney, Beauford, 1952-1953 (Box 70)
    - Delgado, Rafael Rodriguez, 1957-1963 (Box 70)
    - De Lima, Agnes, 1938-1947, undated (Box 70)
    - DeMeyer, Gaynell, 1921 February 12 (Box 70)
    - Denby, Edwin, 1937 (Box 70)
    - De Silver, Margaret, 1939-1940, undated (Box 70)
    - Detroit Public Library, 1951 (Box 70)
    - Dewey, John, undated (Box 70)
    - Dexter, Lewis, 1939-1947 (Box 70)
    - Dial Press, 1939-1945 (Box 70)
    - Dickermann, William J., 1939-1943 (Box 70)
    - Dillon, George, 1946-1947 (Box 70)
    - Dmitri, Ivan, 1961 (Box 70)
    - Döblin, Peter, 1938-1939 (Box 70)
    - Dodson, Owen, 1946, undated (Box 70)
    - Dolbin, B. F., 1946 November 25 (Box 70)
    - Dombrowski, James, 1939 (Box 70)
    - Donohue, Ellen, 1940 (Box 70)
    - Doron, Daniel, 1961-1962, undated (Box 70)
    - Dorr, John Van N. (John Van Nostrand), 1947 April 8 (Box 70)
    - Dos Passos, John, undated (Box 70)
    - Doty, Robert M., 1959-1960 (Box 70)
    - Doubleday, Doran & Company, 1938-1947 (Box 70)
    - Doughty, LeGarde S., 1947-1948 (Box 70)
    - Douglas, Gilean, 1946 (Box 70)
    - Douglas, Prudence W., 1938 (Box 70)
    - Dove, Arthur, 1932-1958 (Box 70)
    - Dowling, Robert W., 1947 April 16 (Box 70)
    - Dreiser, Theodore, 1937-1947 (Box 70)